Life is just one important decision after another.
(阿伏兎)
人生は 重要な選択肢の連続だ｡
Go ahead and see how far your naive decisions can take you.
お前さんたちの 甘い選択肢で
どこまでいけるか➡
やってみるがいい｡
I told you, didn't I? I...
言っただろ？ ｵﾚは…➡
共食いは嫌いなんだ｡
...hate killing my own kind.
["Those Who Stand On Four-Legs Are Beasts. Those Who Stand On Two-Legs, Guts, and Glory Are Men."]
(新八)あ… ｱｲﾂ…➡
H-He...
ﾎﾞｸらを 助けて…｡
saved us...
(神楽)新八…｡
Shinpachi...
神楽ちゃん！
よかった… もとに…｡
Kagura-chan!
Thank god.
You're back to normal...
(神楽)私… 負けてしまったｱﾙ｡
I...lost.
夜兎の本能に… 自分自身に…➡
To my Yato instincts...
To my own self...
殺そうとしてたｱﾙ｡
偉そうなこと言って➡
I tried to kill him.
After all that preaching I did...
結局 私… ｱｲﾂらと 兄貴と…➡
In the end, I wasn't any different...
from them...from my brother.
何も変わらなかったｱﾙ｡
そんなことないよ｡
That's not true.
Kagura-chan, weren't you fighting to protect us?
神楽ちゃん ﾎﾞｸらを護ろうと
戦ってくれたじゃないか｡
ごめん… ﾎﾞｸが弱いばっかりに｡
Sorry...
It's because I was weak that...
ﾎﾞｸが もっと強ければ…｡
If only I were stronger...
I couldn't see anything...
(神楽)何も見えない…
何も聞こえない｡
I couldn't hear anything...
Inside that total darkness, I heard...
ﾄﾞｽ黒い闇の中で聞こえたｱﾙ｡
お前の声が…｡
Your voice...
Shinpachi, you're the one who protected me.
私を護ってくれたのは
新八… お前ｱﾙ｡
私 悔しい…｡
I feel so frustrated.
もっと 強くなりたい…｡
I want to become stronger...
みんなを護れるくらい…｡
Strong enough to protect everyone.
誰にも
自分にも負けないくらい…｡
Strong enough so that I won't lose to anyone, not even myself.
ﾎﾞｸもだよ｡ でも 今は！
I feel the same way.
But, for now!
こんな ﾎﾞｸらの力でも…➡
There are people who need our help.
必要としてくれる
人たちがいるんだ！
ﾎﾞｸらにも
護れるものが 今あるんだ｡
There are things even we can protect.
いつだって 何かを護るたびに
ちょっとずつだけど➡
Every time we protected something,
we became a little stronger, didn't we?
ﾎﾞｸら 強くなってきたじゃないか｡
だから 涙をふいていこう｡
So let's wipe our tears and go.
きっと ﾎﾞｸら…
またひとつ 強くなれるさ！
I'm sure we'll become a little stronger.
♪♪～
(百華たち)ｷｬｰｯ！
(百華)日輪様のもとへ
行かせるな～!!
Don't let them get to Hinowa-sama!
ここで 食い止めろ～!!
Hold them back!
(神威)しつこいなぁ！
So persistent.
(神威)女を殺すのは
趣味じゃないんだよ｡
It's not my style to kill women.
Women may give birth to strong children, right?
女は 強い子を
産むかもしれないだろ？
まぁ ｷﾐらの子供には
期待できないか｡
Well, I suppose I can't expect anything from your children.
(晴太)や… やめろ～!!
S-Stop it!
(晴太)お前… そんなに人を殺して
何が楽しいんだ？
What's so fun about killing people like that?!
なんで そんな ﾍﾗﾍﾗ
人を殺せるんだよ！
How can you kill people and just smile like that?!
(神威)ひどいなぁ～
ここまで連れてきてあげたのに｡
That's harsh. After all I did to bring you here.
それに ｺｲﾂら… ｷﾐの母さんを
ここに閉じ込めてた連中だよ｡
Besides, they're the ones keeping your mother locked up here.
頼んだ覚えは ねえやい…！
I don't remember asking for it!
笑顔は ｵﾚの殺しの作法だ｡
I pay my respects with a smile when killing.
どんな人生であれ
最後は 笑顔で送って➡
Regardless of how their life was, it's appropriate to send them off with a smile,
すこやかに
死なせてやらないとね｡
so they can die soundly.
You could even say that, I intend to kill when I'm smiling.
逆に言えば ｵﾚが笑いかけたときは
殺意があるととってもいい｡
冗談だよ｡
ｵﾚは 子供は殺さない主義なんだ｡
I'm kidding.
I don't believe in killing children.
だって この先
強くなるかもしれないだろう？
After all, they may grow up to be strong.
おいでよ！ ｷﾐも笑うといい｡
Come here.
You should also smile.
お母さんに会うのに…➡
You don't want to meet your mother with such a strained look on your face.
そんな
しけたﾂﾗしてちゃ いけないよ｡
Mom is...here...?
ここに… 母ちゃんが…｡
(神威)８年前… ｷﾐを逃がそうとし
鳳仙に捕まったときから➡
Eight years ago,
when she was captured while trying to help you escape,
ｷﾐの自由と引き替えに
日輪は 自由を奪われた｡
she traded her own freedom for yours.
花魁なんて名ばかりの
ただの飾りさ…｡
She's only a courtesan in name.
鳳仙は 彼女を
客寄せﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞとして使う以外は➡
Hosen locked her up here when he wasn't using her to attract customers.
ここに閉じ込め 客もとらせず
一切の自由を認めなかった｡
She was allowed no clients nor freedom.
ここで 腐って死んでいくことを
日輪に強いたんだ｡
Hosen forced Hinowa to rot to death here.
No, I suppose you could say that Hinowa chose this for herself.
いや… 日輪自身が
それを選んだと言っていい｡
ｷﾐを護るために｡
In order to protect you.
それでも ｷﾐは ここに来た｡
Yet you still came here.
Wasting Hinowa's years of hardship and resolve and putting yourself in danger...
日輪が ｷﾐを護るために
長年耐えてきた 辛苦も覚悟も➡
ﾑﾀﾞにして 危険を冒してまで…｡
それでも 彼女に会いにきた｡
But you still came to see her.
ｷﾐにも ｷﾐの覚悟というものが
あるんだろう？
Which means you're resolved in your own way.
ここから先は ｷﾐの仕事だよ｡
It's your job to go from here on.
(日輪)帰りな｡
Leave.
You won't find what you're seeking here.
ここにｱﾝﾀの求めるものなんて
ありゃしないよ｡
帰りな｡
Leave.
M-Mom...?
か… 母ちゃん｡
Is that you, mom?!
母ちゃんなのか？ 開けてくれよ！
Open up!
You know who I am, right?!
ｵｲﾗだよ｡ わかってんだろ!?
I'm your son, Seita!
ｱﾝﾀの息子の晴太だよ！
Mo...!
I have no son.
(日輪)私に息子なんて
いやしないよ｡
I don't know any dirty brat like you.
ｱﾝﾀみたいな汚いｶﾞｷ 知りやしない｡
Why do you know...?
なんで知ってんだよ｡
Why do you know I'm a dirty brat?
なんで汚いｶﾞｷだって
知ってんだよ？
You were watching me, weren't you?
見てたんだろ？ ｵｲﾗが
いっつも下からｱﾝﾀを見てたとき➡
Whenever I was looking up at you from below,
ｱﾝﾀも ｵｲﾗのこと見てたんだろ？
you were also looking at me, right?
何度叫んでも
答えてくれなかったけど➡
You never responded when I shouted to you,
ﾎﾝﾄは ｵｲﾗを巻き込むまいと➡
but that was so I wouldn't get involved.
You were struggling to keep your mouth shut, weren't you?!
必死に声が出そうになるのを
我慢してたんだろ？
母ちゃん ｵｲﾗ 何も知らなかった｡
Mom...
I had no idea...
母ちゃんが こんな所で
苦しんでるなんて｡
that you were suffering here.
I always wondered why I was the only unfortunate one.
なんで ｵｲﾗばっかり
こんな不幸なんだろうって｡
じいちゃんと
貧しい生活してたときも➡
When I was living in poverty with Grandpa...
じいちゃんが死んで
独りぼっちになったときも➡
When I was all alone after Grandpa died...
I blamed it all on you for abandoning me.
全部 ｵｲﾗを捨てた
母ちゃんのせいにしてた｡
I had no idea.
ｵｲﾗ 何も知らなかった｡
I didn't know anything at all.
何もわかっちゃいなかった｡
That you were protecting me this whole time.
母ちゃんが ずっとｵｲﾗのこと➡
護ってくれてたなんて…｡
Now it's my turn!
(晴太)今度は ｵｲﾗの番だ！
Now it's my turn to save you, mom!
(晴太)今度はｵｲﾗが ここから➡
母ちゃんを救い出す｡
Now I'm going to protect you, mom!!
今度は ｵｲﾗが母ちゃんを護る｡
もう こんな所に絶対に
置いてったりしない！
I won't leave you in there!!
This time we'll leave this place for sure!
今度こそ ここから出るんだ｡
Both of us are going up together!
親子で一緒に 上に行くんだ！
So mom...
だから母ちゃん
ここを開けてくれ！
Open the door!
Please, mom!
お願いだ 母ちゃん！ 母ちゃん!!
Mom!!
Mo...!
Stop it!
(日輪)やめとくれ｡
Your mom isn't here.
ｱﾝﾀの母ちゃんなんて
ここには いない｡
Didn't I tell you that?
そう言ってんだろ｡
M-Mom...
母ちゃん｡
That's not true.
(鳳仙)そんなことあるまい｡
If you want to see her so badly, I'll let you.
そんなに会いたくば
会わせてやろう｡
Personally...
(鳳仙)このﾜｼが｡
H-Hosen!
ほ… 鳳仙！
あちゃ～ 見つかっちった｡
Oops, we've been found.
ﾌｯ 連れて行くなら連れて行け｡
Take her with you if you want.
Child, that is your mother.
ﾜｯﾊﾟ それがお前の母親だ｡
Hinowa isn't your mother.
お前の母親は 日輪ではない｡
Your mother left this world long ago.
とうの昔に この世におらんわ｡
何を言ってるんだ？
What are you...talking about...
You think a courtesan of Yoshiwara could give birth to a child unnoticed?
吉原の花形たる花魁が➡
誰にも露見することなく
子を産むなど➡
できるわけがあるまい｡
Eight years ago, a prostitute became pregnant with a child.
８年前 １人の遊女が子を孕んだ｡
だが 吉原で子を孕めば
腹の子ごと始末される｡
But becoming pregnant in Yoshiwara means death for both.
So a number of the women hid her and secretly assisted the birth.
そこで一部の女たちは
その女をかくまい➡
人知れず密かに
その子をとりあげたのだ｡
Yes...
そう それがお前だ｡ ﾜｯﾊﾟ！
That was you, child!
Your mother was weak and died after giving birth to you.
お前の母親は衰弱し➡
お前を産み落とすと同時に死んだ｡
Unfortunately, the woman over there isn't your mother.
残念ながら そこにいるのは
お前の母親ではない｡
Dreaming of becoming a mother, yet couldn't.
母に憧れながら
しかし 母になることも叶わない➡
Just a pathetic women who immersed herself in playing a mother role.
母親ごっこに興ずる
ただの哀れな女だ｡
Why...
(日輪)どうして… どうして
こんな所に来ちまったんだい？
Why did you come to this place?
なんで こんな所に｡
Why did you come?
ほっときゃ よかったんだ➡
You should have just forgotten about someone like me.
私のことなんて…｡
Just knowing you lived up there for the rest of us would have been enough.
私たちの分まで
上で元気でいてくれりゃ➡
それでよかったんだ｡
I'm not worth risking your life to protect.
ｱﾝﾀが 命張って護るほどの
もんじゃないんだよ わたしゃ｡
ﾌﾝｯ お前の母親など
この世のどこにもおらんわ｡
You won't find your mother anywhere in this world.
Now that you understand, take that memento of her and get lost.
わかったら
その形見だけ持って消えろ｡
それとも 冥土で母親に
会いたいというのなら別の話だが｡
Of course, it's a different story if you wish to see your mother in the afterlife.
(鳳仙)ﾌﾌﾌ…｡
(扉に ぶつかる音)
I have a mother!
(晴太)母親ならいる！ ここに!!
Right here!
My mom is alive!
ｵｲﾗの母ちゃんならいる！
ここに!!
Right here!
The one who delivered me from this eternal darkness to the surface!
常夜の闇から
ｵｲﾗを地上に産み落としてくれた➡
The one who risked her life to give birth to me!
命を張って ｵｲﾗを産んでくれた！
血なんか
繋がってなくても関係ない！
It doesn't matter if we aren't related by blood!
ｵｲﾗの母ちゃんは…
この人だぁ～！
This person is my mom!
(鳳仙)あきらめの悪いﾜｯﾊﾟだ｡
You don't know when to give up, child.
仕方あるまい｡
I have no choice.
Go meet your real mother in the underworld.
黄泉で本物の親と
対面するがいい…｡
うわっ！
Th-This is...
ｺｲﾂは…｡
(銀時)ｵｲｵｲ 聞いてねえぜ｡
Hey, I wasn't told about this.
吉原一の女がいるっていうから
来てみりゃ～よ｡
I came cause they said the best woman in Yoshiwara was here.
どうやら ｺﾌﾞつきだったらしい｡
But it looks like she's got a kid.
その涙が何よりの証拠だ｡
Those tears prove it.
M-Mom...?
母ちゃん…｡
店長 新しい娘 頼まぁ｡
Hey manager, get me a different girl.
どぎつい SMﾌﾟﾚｲにも
耐えられるﾔﾂをよ｡
One that can withstand some really rough SM play.
ｷｻﾏ… 誰だ｡
Who are you?
Nobody special.
(銀時)
なに ただの女好きの遊び人よ…｡
Just a girl-loving playboy.
ぎ… ぎ…｡
Gi...
銀さん！
Gin-san!!
何してんだ ｱﾎんだら｡
What are you doing, dummy?
ｵﾚはいいから さっさと行け｡
Just get going and don't worry about me.
But...
でも… 行っても… いいの？
Is it okay for me to go?
ｵｲﾗみたいな汚いｶﾞｷが
あんな きれいな人…➡
Is it okay for a dirty brat like me
to call such a beautiful person my mom?
母ちゃんて 呼んでもいいの？
散々ぬかしといて
何 言ってんだ ﾃﾒｴは！
You called her that all this time and now you're asking?
呼んでやれ！
Call to her.
Yell "Mom" from the bottom of your heart.
腹の底から ｢母ちゃん｣ってよ｡
M-Mom...
か… 母ちゃん…｡
(日輪)いいのかい…｡
Are you sure?
血も繋がってないのに…
こんな薄汚れた女を➡
Calling someone not related to you...
a dirty woman like me, your mom?
母ちゃんなんて呼んでも…｡
母ちゃん…｡
Mom...
(日輪)いいのかい…｡
Are you sure?
Calling someone who wasn't able to do anything for you...
今まで ｱﾝﾀに
何もしてやれなかった私を➡
母ちゃんなんて呼んでも…｡
a woman like me, as your mom?
母ちゃん…｡
Mom...
(日輪)いいのかい 私なんかが
ｱﾝﾀの母ちゃんになっても…｡
Are you sure?
A woman like me becoming your mom...?
Mom!
母ちゃん～!!
(日輪)晴太～!!
Seita!
(泣き声)
(神威)あれは あのときいた…｡
He was the one from when...
へぇ… 生きてたんだ｡
Wow, so he survived.
そうか ｷｻﾏがﾜｯﾊﾟの雇った浪人｡
I see.
You're the ronin the child hired.
ﾜｼの街を好き勝手に
やってくれたのは ぬしか？
Are you the one who's been running wild around my city?
Running wild?
好き勝手？ 冗談よせよ｡
Don't make me laugh.
I haven't bought a single woman.
ｵﾚは女の１人も買っちゃいねえよ｡
そうか ならば
これから酒宴を用意してやる｡
I see.
Then I'll prepare a banquet for you.
A banquet of blood.
血の宴をな！
過分な心遣い ありがたいが➡
I appreciate the generous gesture, but I'll have to pass.
そいつは遠慮するぜ｡
I can't enjoy a drink while looking at an old geezer's receding hairline.
じじいのＶ字の生え際
見ながら酒飲んでも➡
なんにも うまかねえ！
I can't enjoy a drink at a place like this.
こんな所で酒飲んだって
なんにも うまかねえ｡
確かに よくまあ
これだけ あちこちから➡
Yeah, you did a fine job with bringing in this many babes.
べっぴんさんを
集めてきたもんだよ｡
だが どんだけ美女を集めようが
どんだけ美酒を用意しようが➡
But it doesn't matter how many beautiful women,
or how much fine liquor you have.
I won't drink a single drop in your place.
ｵﾚは ﾃﾒｴの国で酒なんざ
一滴たりとも飲まねえ｡
鎖で繋がれた女から
酒なんて注がれても➡
I can't enjoy a drink poured by women in chains.
なんにも うまかねえんだよ！
泣きながら酒なんてつがれても
なんにも うまかねえんだよ｡
I can't enjoy a drink poured by someone in tears.
ばばあだらけの薄汚ねえｽﾅｯｸでも
笑って酌してくれんなら➡
I'd take a crappy snack joint full of old ladies instead,
if they serve me with a smile.
ｵﾚは それがいい｡
I'd take a bar run by a vicious cabaret girl instead,
悪辣なｷｬﾊﾞ嬢が はびこる
ぼったくりﾊﾞｰでも➡
みんなが笑って酒飲めるなら
ｵﾚは それがいい｡
if everyone could drink and laugh.
美女も美酒も 屋根さえもねえ
野っぱらでも➡
I'd take a field in the middle of nowhere with no women, wine, or even a roof instead,
月見て
安い酒飲めるなら それがいい｡
if we could drink cheap liquor and watch the moon.
女の涙は…｡
A woman's tears...
are too much to go with drinking.
酒の肴にゃ辛すぎらあ｡
鎖を断ち切りにきたか｡
So you came to shatter those chains?
この夜王の鎖から日輪を…｡
To free Hinowa...the woman of Yoshiwara from the King of the Night?
吉原の女たちを
解き放とうというのか｡
It's not that big a deal.
そんな
大そうなものじゃねえ｡
ｵﾚはただ 酒が飲みてえだけだ｡
I just want a drink.
天下の花魁様に 立派な笑顔つきで
酌してもらいたくてなぁ｡
And have the finest courtesan serve it to me with one great smile.
How amusing.
(神威)こりゃ おもしろい｡
Picking a fight with the King of the Night for the sake of a drink.
たかだか 酒一杯のために
夜王に ｹﾝｶを売るとは➡
地球にも なかなか
おもしろいﾔﾂがいるもんだね｡
Guess Earth has its share of amusing people.
Right, Boss Hosen?
(神威)ねぇ 鳳仙の旦那｡
(神威)ﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Ooh, scary.
おぉ こわっ｡
そんなに 怒らないでくださいよ｡
Don't be so angry.
心配しなくても
もう ｼﾞｬﾏはしませんよ｡
Don't worry. I won't interfere with you anymore.
Kamui! What are you after?
神威 ｷｻﾏ 何が目的だ！
(鳳仙)
ﾜｼの命をとろうとした次は➡
After attempting to take my life, you help that child by taking him to Hinowa.
ﾜｯﾊﾟを手助けし
日輪のもとまで手引き｡
You want to interfere with me that badly?
そうまでして ﾜｼの
ｼﾞｬﾏをしたいのか それとも➡
Or perhaps...
母を求める ﾜｯﾊﾟの姿を見て
遠き日でも思い出したか？
Watching that child long for his mother brought back memories of the past?
You now feel like atoning for abandoning your sick mother?
(鳳仙)病の母親を
捨ててきたお前が➡
罪滅ぼしでも
する気になったか？ ﾌﾌﾌﾌ…｡
ﾌｯ 何を世迷ごとを｡
What nonsense.
(神威)夜王を腑抜けにした女➡
I was wondering what sort of woman could turn the King of the Night into a fool,
いったい どれほどの
女かと思えば…｡
(神威)ﾎﾞﾛ雑巾にすがる
ただの みじめな女とは｡
but she turns out to be a miserable wretch clinging to a dirty brat.
The sun of Yoshiwara? Yeah, right.
吉原の太陽が聞いて呆れる｡
This isn't it.
違うんだよ｡
ｵﾚの求めている強さは｡
The strength I seek isn't for some cheap crap like this.
こんな
しみったれたものじゃない｡
Like not hesitating to kill your own sister or father.
妹だろうが 親父だろうが
構わずぶっ殺す｡
そういうﾔﾂかい｡
Is that what you mean?
Talk about ironic.
皮肉じゃねえか｡ 実の妹を
殺そうとする兄貴もいりゃ➡
If there's a brother willing to kill his real sister,
血は 繋がっていなくとも➡
there are people with bonds stronger than those between a parent and a child.
親子より強い絆で
繋がってる連中もいる｡
どっちが本物の家族かなんて
知りゃしねえがな｡
Who knows which would be considered the real family.
Very amusing.
(鳳仙)おもしろいではないか｡
(鳳仙)
その絆とやらの強さ…➡
Why don't you show me how strong those bonds are?
見せてもらおうではないか！
Whether you can release them from my chains...
(鳳仙)ｷｻﾏが ﾜｼの鎖から
解き放てるか…｡
(鳳仙)ﾜｼが ﾔﾂらの絆を
断ち切れるか…｡
or for me to break through their bonds.
勝負といこうではないか！
Let's see who will win!
地球人ふぜいに
この夜王の鎖➡
Can a mere Earthling shatter the chains...
断ち切れるか？
of the King of the Night?!
A chain made from a perverted old man's wet dreams?
ｴﾛじじいの先走り汁の糸で
できたような鎖なんざ…➡
一太刀で しめえだ｡
I'll break it with a single strike.
Every night has to end eventually.
明けねえ夜なんざ
この世にはねえ｡
It's time for this city to see dawn.
この街にも
朝日が昇るときが来たんだ｡
The King of the Night can watch the sunrise,
夜の王は 日の出とともに！
and go nighty night!!
おねんねしやがれ!!
Gin-san!
銀さん!!
♪♪～
ぎ 銀さん！
G-Gin-san!
Ah...
ほう…｡
So you blocked my attack?
(鳳仙)ﾜｼの一撃を止めたか｡
《ふさけやがって…｡
What the hell...
One hit...
たった一撃
たった一太刀 受けただけで➡
One strike and it feels like...
体じゅうから 気力も体力も
全部 そぎ落とされた気分だ…｡
my body's lost all its energy and stamina!
夜王 鳳仙｡
Hosen, King of the Night.
This is the power of the man once known as the King of the Yato?
ｺｲﾂが 夜兎の王と呼ばれた男の
力ってわけかい》
(神威)すごい すごい｡
Oh, wow.
あの 夜王相手に
10秒もつなんて｡
You lasted ten seconds against the King of the Night.
ｺｲﾂは おもしろくなってきた｡
This is getting interesting.
がんばってよ おにいさん
ｵﾚ 応援したくなってきちゃった｡
Good luck, mister.
I feel like rooting for you now.
Don't look down on me, you damn kid.
なめんじゃねえ ｸｿｶﾞｷ｡
10秒どころか
天寿まっとうしてやるよ｡
Ten seconds? Hell, I'll last till I die of old age.
孫に囲まれて
穏やかに死んでやるよ この野郎｡
I'll die peacefully while surrounded by grandchildren, you bastard!
ｷｻﾏの天寿など
とうに尽きておるわ｡
Your life has already ended.
この吉原に この夜王に
たてついたときからな！
The second you decided to oppose Yoshiwara...the King of the Night!
(鳳仙)ふんっ！
♪♪～
《骨がきしむ｡
筋肉が泣きわめく｡
My bones are grating...
My muscles are crying in pain...
指一本 筋肉の筋 一本たりとも
力を抜けねえ｡
I can't relax a single finger, a single muscle!
一瞬で潰される》
I'll be crushed in the next moment!
♪♪～
うわぁぁぁ～っ!!
《呼吸すら…
まばたきさえ する間もねえ！
No time to breath...or even blink!
一撃で…
体と心を 引き剥がされる！》
A single blow forces my soul from my body!
♪♪～
ぐわっ!! ぐぉぉぉ～っ!!
(晴太)銀さん!!
Gin-san!
あ～りゃりゃ｡ もう おしまいか｡
つまんないの｡
What, over already?
That's no fun.
ﾌﾌﾌﾌ！ でかい口を 叩くだけは
あるらしいな｡
It seems you're not just all talk.
あくまで
地球のなかだけの話だが➡
Within Earth standards, that is.
しょせん 我ら 天人から➡
Of course, you samurai wouldn't be able to shatter my chains,
国さえ護れなかった ｷｻﾏら 侍に➡
我が鎖 断ち切ることなど
できるはずも なかったのだ！
when you couldn't even protect your own nation from the Amanto.
獅子は 縄張り争いに負ければ➡
When a lion loses a turf war,
縄張りとともに
己の保有する雌をも 明け渡す｡
it must turn over its land and its females.
あっ… あぁ～っ!!
わかるか!!
Do you understand?
ｷｻﾏら侍には もう 居場所も➡
You samurai no longer have a home,
その手で 女を抱く権利すらも
ありは しないのだ｡
or the right to hold women.
Because your lands and females all became ours long ago!
とっくの昔に 縄張りも雌も➡
皆 ﾜｼらのものに
なってしまったのだから｡
That's right.
そう…
この街も 女たちも 日輪も➡
This city, its women, and Hinowa all belong to the King of the Night!
すべて この 夜王のもの！
They're chained up as my pets.
ﾔﾂらは
ﾜｼの鎖に つながれた 飼い犬だ｡
どこにも 逃げられはせぬわ！
They cannot escape anywhere.
And you losers don't have the right to stop me!
そして ｷｻﾏら負け犬に
これを止める権利は ない!!
悪いのは
何も 護ることのできなかった➡
It's your fault for being too weak to protect anything!
ｷｻﾏら 弱者なのだからな！
負け犬は 負け犬らしく➡
A loser should act like one and just suck on his thumb...
指をくわえて
見ておれば よいのだ｡
この国が… 女たちが…➡
and watch as this nation and its women are violated by the stronger ones!
我ら強者に 蹂躙される様を!!
In the other world, where your comrades are waiting for you!
先にいった仲間たちと一緒に
あの世でな!!
♪♪～
負けてなんかいねえよ
ｵﾚたちは…｡
We haven't lost...
...I'm still fighting!
今も 戦ってるよ… ｵﾚは!!
ｷ… ｷｻﾏ～!!
You son of a...!!
ぐわっ！
(晴太)銀さん!!
来るな!!
Gin-san!!
Stay back!!
なにしてやがる ﾃﾒｴ！
What are you doing, idiot?
Get going already.
さっさと 行かねえか！
Take your mom and get outta here!
母ちゃん連れて
ここから 早く逃げんだよ！
N-No!
嫌だ!! 銀さんを 置いて➡
Are you telling me to run away by myself and leave you behind?!
ｵｲﾗだけ
逃げ出せっていうのかよ！
I can't do that after getting you involved in all of this!
(晴太)そんなﾏﾈ…
こんなことに巻き込んで…➡
そんなﾏﾈ 絶対にできるかよ!!
Getting me involved?
巻き込んだ？
I butted in on my own.
勝手に 顔 つっこんだの
間違いだろ…｡
Get going.
行けよ｡ ﾃﾒｴら 親子に
何かあっちゃ ｵﾚたちゃ…➡
If something happens to the two of you,
we'll have come here for nothing.
ここまで なにしに来たのか
わからねえよ…｡
嫌だ… そんなの 絶対 嫌だ!!
No...!
No way!
役には立たないけど…
ｵｲﾗが 銀さんを助ける！
I may be useless,
but I'll help you!
ずっと 最後まで 一緒にいる!!
I'll stay with you until the end!
You stupid...
ﾃﾒｴは…！
(晴太)銀さん 言ったじゃない！
You said so!
That there were bonds stronger than family, even when people aren't related by blood?
血は 繋がってなくとも
家族より 強い絆があるって…｡
そうさ… 血なんか 関係あるかよ｡
That's right.
Blood doesn't matter.
You all reformed me from being a thief.
ｵｲﾗを泥棒から
足 洗わせてくれた…｡
まともな生活を
送れるようにしてくれた…｡
You all taught me how to lead a respectable life.
独りぼっちの ｵｲﾗと
一緒にいてくれた…｡
You all kept me...from being all alone.
短い間だったけど 楽しかった…｡
It wasn't very long, but it was fun.
じいちゃんが 死んでから
初めてだった…➡
Ever since Grandpa died, I never had that much fun.
あんなに 楽しかったのは…｡
(晴太)母ちゃんとは
何も変わらない…｡
Just like Mom...
みんなは… 銀さんは…➡
Everybody...Gin-san...
You're all like family to me!
ｵｲﾗにとっちゃ
大切な家族なんだよ!!
大切なことを
いっぱい教えてくれた…➡
The one and only people who taught me what's important!
かけがえのない人たちなんだよ！
And you're telling me to abandon you here?!
それを こんな所に
捨てていけっていうのかよ！
こんな所に 見殺しに
していけっていうのかよ!!
To let you die in this place?!
ｿｲﾂが 聞けただけで…
ｵﾚは もう 十分だよ…｡
Hearing you say that is more than enough...
行ってくれ｡
Get going.
ｵﾚを また
負け犬に させないでくれよ…｡
Don't make me into a loser again.
ぎ… 銀さん…｡
Gin-san...
ぎ…➡
Gi...
Gin...!
ぎ…➡
Gin-san!!
銀さ～～ん!!
[Preview]
What a joke this is.
After all that big talking, look at you!
Where's that sun you promised?
I was a fool for expecting anything from you.
You...stinkin' big bluff!
[The next episode: "Don't Trust Bedtime Stories"]
[There was a heart-wrenching reason why Hinowa was stuck there.]
[Inspired by Gintoki's words, Seita sets out to rescue his mother all by himself.]